



SUMMARY

in /khaykingleb

MLOps/DevOps Engineer with 3.5+ years of software engineering experience. Specialized in boosting model performance, reducing costs by >\$10k monthly, deploying scalable solutions to apps with >30k DAU, and optimizing data and workflow pipelines. Integrated state-of-the-art technologies across cloud and on-premise environments. Background in distributed systems, speech processing, speech synthesis, natural language processing, and finance.

EXPERIENCE

MLOps/DevOps Engineer at iClerk

San Francisco, USA (Remote)

Silicon Valley startup focusing on automating tedious tasks for B2B

July 2023 — Present

- Refined the ensemble model for transcription and speaker diarization, achieving an 11x speed increase & improved accuracy
- o Innovated a scalable cost-efficient inference pipeline, reducing operational costs by 5x for one-hour meeting processing
- Architected a K3s-based GPU cluster that cut GPU hosting costs by >50%
- o Established IaC monitoring & alerting for 4 K8s clusters with Grafana Alloy OTel Collector, reducing downtime and errors

ML/MLOps Engineer at NeiroAI

Tbilisi, Georgia

 $Generative\ AI\ startup\ with\ \$150M\ and\ \$200M\ B2C\ app\ exits$

November 2022 — March 2024

- $\circ \ \, \text{Built a REST/gRPC API for speech, handling } \textbf{60k+inference} \ \, \text{and } \textbf{fine-tune requests} \ \, \text{per hour with } \textbf{priority queuing} \\$
- Researched and deployed state-of-the-art multilingual, emotional text-to-speech and voice conversion models in 44 kHz
- \circ Created a service for fast speech model fine-tuning to any voice in under 1 minute
- \circ Terraformized critical speech infrastructure with >4000 lines of IaC
- Introduced MLOps/DevOps best practices to a 20+ developer engineering division

Data Scientist at DiviAI

San Francisco, USA (Remote)

September 2021 — July 2022

 $Silicon\ Valley\ startup\ building\ a\ financial\ data\ aggregator\ for\ the\ US\ market$

- \circ Engineered a PySpark pipeline for scraping S&P 500 news to estimate investor **sentiment with BERT**-like models
- o Developed ETL pipelines that aggregate data from 150+ financial API endpoints
- o Designed a listwise learning-to-rank recommendation system for stocks, optimizing long-short strategies
- $\circ\,$ Adopted a Glicko rating system to rank Russell 3000 CEOs

PROJECTS

Deep Learning for Audio

- o Implemented QuartzNet, FastSpeech, and HiFi-GAN from scratch based on arXiv papers
- o Applied compression techniques to keyword spotting models, achieving 11x size reduction and 9x speed increase

Canonical Huffman Archiver

 \circ Developed an ASCII archiver in C++ with Conan-based auto-build system

Stochastic Optimization Methods

- o Constructed Particle Swarm Optimization for performance testing on Rosenbrock and Ackley benchmark functions
- $\circ\,$ Applied ${\bf Genetic}$ ${\bf Algorithm}$ for solving the NP-hard Traveling Salesman Problem

EDUCATION

NRU "Higher School of Economics"

Moscow, Russia

B.S. with summa cum laude in Economics and Data Science

 $September\ 2018\ --\ July\ 2022$

- $\circ~$ Top 3% among 450 students
- Relevant coursework: C++, Python, R, Machine Learning 1, Machine Learning 2, Large Scale Machine Learning, Deep Learning,
 Deep Learning in Audio Processing, Reinforcement Learning, Calculus, Linear Algebra, Probability Theory, Mathematical
 Statistics, Stochastic Processes, Econometrics, Microeconometrics, Differential & Difference Equations, IFRS, Corporate Finance

MISCELLANEOUS

CFA Level 1

• Passed in February 2021, scoring in the top 10% of candidates worldwide

Teaching Assistant at NRU "Higher School of Economics"

o Facilitated course coordination in **Probability**, **Statistics**, and **Machine Learning** from 2020 to 2022

SKILLS

- o Languages: Python, Rust, Go, C++, SQL, TypeScript, JavaScript
- o Frontend: Remix, React, Tailwind, Vercel
- o Backend: gRPC, REST, AsyncIO, FastAPI, JWT, Node.js
- o Builds: Make, CMake, Conan, Poetry, Pnpm, Npm
- o DevOps: Terraform, Ansible, Docker, Kubernetes, K3s, AWS, GCP, Grafana, Prometheus, Loki, Nginx, Acme, ArgoCD, CI/CD
- MLOps: DVC, NVIDIA Triton, Ollama, LangChain, TorchScript, ONNX, TensorRT, CoreML, Gradio
- o DE: Hadoop, Spark, Databricks, Polars, Kafka, Celery, RabbitMQ
- o Storage: Redis, PostgreSQL, PGVector, Sqitch, S3, R2, Supabase, Airtable
- o R&D: PyTorch, Lightning, Hydra, W&B, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, SciPy